<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Resume>
    <Header>
        <Name>Charles F. Hayes</Name>
        <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
        <Email>cfhayes16@gmail.com</Email>
        <Phone>303.929.8652</Phone>
        <Github>github.com/ch88251</Github>
    </Header>
    
    <Summary>
    With over 20 years in software engineering, I possess comprehensive expertise across full-stack development, 
    infrastructure automation, and test automation. My background includes extensive work in enterprise Java 
    development and asynchronous messaging systems with JMS. I helped clients modernize their legacy applications 
    to more modern software architectures within agile frameworks. Committed to continuous learning, I have a proven 
    track record of adapting to diverse tech stacks and delivering successful projects that meet rigorous demands.
    </Summary>

    <Skills>
        <Advanced>
            <Skill>Java, JEE</Skill>
            <Skill>Hibernate, JPA</Skill>
            <Skill>SOAP, REST</Skill>
            <Skill>Microservices</Skill>
            <Skill>Kubernetes, Helm</Skill>
            <Skill>Docker, Docker Compose</Skill>
            <Skill>Jenkins</Skill>
            <Skill>HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript</Skill>
        </Advanced>
        <Intermediate>
            <Skill>Python</Skill>
            <Skill>Spring, Spring Boot</Skill>
            <Skill>Quarkus</Skill>
            <Skill>React</Skill>
            <Skill>Ansible</Skill>
        </Intermediate>
        <Beginner>
            <Skill>C++, CMake</Skill>
            <Skill>GoogleTest, GoogleMock</Skill>
            <Skill>PostgreSQL</Skill>
            <Skill>Oracle</Skill>
            <Skill>MySQL</Skill>
            <Skill>MongoDB</Skill>
            <Skill>Next.js</Skill>
            <Skill>Tailwind CSS</Skill>
        </Beginner>
    </Skills>

    <Clearance>Secret Clearance</Clearance>

    <RecentCourses>
        <Course>
            <Date>April, 2024</Date>
            <Name>Elastic Engineer Training</Name>
            <Details>6 hours, classroom</Details>
        </Course>
        <Course>
            <Date>April, 2020</Date>
            <Name>Building Scalable Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud</Name>
            <Details>12 hours, Coursera, Grade: 99%</Details>
        </Course>
        <Course>
            <Date>November, 2018</Date>
            <Name>Continuous Delivery and DevOps</Name>
            <Details>8 hours, Coursera, Grade: 85%</Details>
        </Course>
    </RecentCourses>

    <Certifications>
        <Certification>
            <Name></Name>
            <Date></Date>
        </Certification>
    </Certifications>

    <Jobs>
        <Name>Professional Experience</Name>
        <Job>
            <Company>Frontier Technology</Company>
            <Title>Senior Full-Stack Developer</Title>
            <Period>July 2023 - Present</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed ansible playbooks for automating the installation and configuration of critical infrastructure.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented a new software capability that allows cyber security analysts to search and 
                preserve PCAP files for future analysis.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Configured an ILM policy in elastic search to resolve a critical defect where packetbeat 
                indexes were filling up and not rolling over properly.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created cypress tests for end-to-end validation, significantly enhancing our 
                software’s quality assurance by closing a critical testing gap
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Actalent / Boeing</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>July 2020 - July 2023</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Proficient in configuring and deploying containerized applications within Kubernetes clusters, 
                optimizing resource utilization and ensuring seamless operation.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Demonstrated expertise in managing essential Kubernetes resources using manifest files for creating 
                pods, services, deployments, secrets, configmaps, persistent volumes, persistent volume claims, 
                facilitating efficient deployment and configuration.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed a test coverage dashboard to help the team understand the test coverage of the test automation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>        
        <Job>
            <Company>ITEC</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>June 2017 - January 2018</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Worked closely with systems engineers, integrators, testers and customers to design a 
                set of standards and guidelines for building CI/CD pipelines.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Learned the Phillip Kruechten's 4+1 architectural view model and applied it to my 
                software design and documentation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Colorado Interactive</Company>
            <Title>Lead Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>Auguust 2014 - April 2016</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Played a pivotal role in mentoring junior engineers, fostering a culture of collaboration and 
                continuous learning through code reviews, pair programming sessions, and knowledge-sharing 
                initiatives. This contributed to enhanced team productivity and skill development, ensuring the 
                growth and success of the engineering team.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Redesigned the web application for registering businesses in Colorado by streamlining 
                the process for registering a business with Colorado Department of Labor and Employment, 
                Department of Revenue and Secretary of State. Previously business owners had to fill out 
                forms in two different web applications.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Designed and implemented a flexible architecture that empowered each court office to access and manage 
                its distinct data, while dynamically adapting the user interface to reflect the court's unique branding 
                elements. This initiative resulted in a cost-effective solution that unified the user experience across 
                multiple court entities while preserving individualized branding identities.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>February 2013 - December 2013</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed a robust software solution enabling Charles Schwab advisors to generate 
                comprehensive PDF reports for clients. These reports showcase current and proposed 
                investment portfolios, empowering clients to make informed decisions about their 
                financial investments.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Collaborated with cross-functional teams to implement an enterprise logging initiative. 
                This initiative aggregated logs from diverse applications and established a centralized 
                log viewer using Splunk. The centralized view allowed engineers and support teams to 
                efficiently troubleshoot issues and swiftly identify root causes by providing real-time 
                insights into events across multiple servers and applications.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems / McKesson</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>January 2009 to February 2013</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed new web service contracts (WSDL) and designed message payloads and 
                transformations for McKesson's Healthcare Management System.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Played a pivotal role in the design and implementation of a Service-Oriented Architecture 
                (SOA), leveraging web services to enhance interoperability and collaboration across healthcare entities.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Collaborated with cross-functional teams to interpret and implement regulatory requirements, 
                guaranteeing that the healthcare integration application met the necessary standards and regulations 
                set forth by the ARRA initiative.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
    </Jobs>

    <AdditionalJobs>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems</Company>
            <Title>Lead Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>September 2019 - July 2020</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Consulted with various clients in the United States to advise and mentor technical 
                staff on continuous delivery and continuous testing practices. Provided hand-on labs 
                for developing effective test automation frameworks.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Provided weekly demonstrations of our test automation and presented reports 
                for requirement coverage and testing progress.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Demonstrated the successful execution of our automated tests in an Azure 
                DevOps pipeline.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>T-Mobile Inc</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>July 2018 - September 2019</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Designed and developed a robust test automation framework that uses Gradle, Java 11, 
                JUnit5, Selenide and Allure. This framework was instrumental in ensuring the reliability 
                and quality of our Layer3 TV STB (Set Top Box) product's user interface.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented unit tests using Jest to enhance code quality and identify potential issues 
                early in the development cycle. This proactive approach significantly contributed to a 
                reduction in production defects.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Championed test-driven development (TDD) practices within the organization by delivering 
                a highly informative "Lunch and Learn" session. Shared insights on the benefits of TDD and 
                practical strategies for its implementation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>NetPolarity</Company>
            <Title>Java Engineer (Contracted at Charles Schwab)</Title>
            <Period>January 2008 - December 2008</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed new web services for aggregating gain/loss data for Charles Schwab's
                PortfolioCenter product.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed automated API tests using SoapUI.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Extended the capabilities of SoapUI by developing custom plugins in Java.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Electronic Data Systems</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>April 2005 - August 2007</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Successfully helped a team build a Message Oriented Middleware solution for a client. 
                Replaced an old CORBA architecture with a more modern JMS architecture.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented security in a single sign-on application. Configured Weblogic with 2-way SSL, 
                created Java keystores, and configured time synchronization and security policies in 
                Weblogic.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Sun Microsystems</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>January 2000 - April 2005</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed "Fact" classes and parsers for a rule engine used to perform 
                predictive analytics.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Learned a new programming language called KPL (Knowledge Predicate Language) 
                which I used in the rule engine for determining risk outcomes.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Responsible for requirements gathering, OOAD, development, testing, and deployment 
                of a 3-tier web application.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented software design patterns in a web application that empowered the 
                customer to generate a wide variety of report types.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>      
    </AdditionalJobs>
    <Education>
        <School>
            <Name>Regis University</Name>
            <Period>2000 - 2002</Period>
            <Major>Completed 27 semester hours in Computer Science as funding permitted.</Major>
        </School>
        <School>
            <Name>Spartan College of Aeronautics and Engineering</Name>
            <Period>1990 - 1992</Period>
            <Major>Avionics, 3.0 GPA, Obtained FCC License</Major>
        </School>
    </Education>    
    
</Resume>
