<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Resume>
    <Header>
        <Name>Charles F. Hayes</Name>
        <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
        <Address>685 Wuthering Heights Drive</Address>
        <City>Colorado Springs</City>
        <State>CO</State>
        <Zip>80921</Zip>
        <Phone>303.929.8652</Phone>
        <Email>charles.hayes@cfhayes.com</Email>
    </Header>
    
    <Section>
        <Name>Professional Profile</Name>
        <Description>
            Results-driven software engineer with over 20 years of hands-on experience. 
            Proven expertise in designing and implementing robust continuous delivery 
            pipelines and pioneering continuous testing practices. A seasoned professional 
            in infrastructure automation and full-stack software test automation. Eager to 
            contribute my wealth of knowledge and skills to a dynamic team, driving excellence 
            in software quality and delivery.
        </Description>
    </Section>
    
    <Section>
        <Name>Technical Skills</Name>
        <Description>
        Java, Python, Javascript, Typescript, Pytest, JUnit5, Docker, 
        Docker Compose, Kubernetes, Helm, Ansible, Spring, Spring Boot, Quarkus, Microservices, 
        REST, JSON, Gradle, Maven, Jenkins, Serenity BDD, Cucumber, Selenium Webdriver, 
        Azure DevOps, AWS, SQL, UML, Technical Writing, Jira, XRay, Confluence
        </Description>
    </Section>
    
    <Section>
        <Name>Professional Experience</Name>
        <Job>
            <Company>Frontier Technology</Company>
            <Title>Advisory Software Developer</Title>
            <Period>July 2023 - Present</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created an ansible playbook to automate the installation and configuration of Neo4j.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created an ansible playbook to automate the installation and configuration of a cyber attack analytics web application.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created an ansible playbook to automate the installation and configuration of a disk cleaner application.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Boeing</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>July 2020 - July 2023</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Integration, testing and troubleshooting of microservices in a Kubernetes environment.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created tests with Python and Pytest to test the functionality of the microservices.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed a test coverage dashboard to help the team understand the test coverage of the test automation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>        
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems Global Services</Company>
            <Title>Lead Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>September 2019 - July 2020</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Consulted with various clients in the United States to advise and mentor technical 
                staff on continuous delivery and continuous testing practices. Provided hand-on labs 
                for developing effective test automation frameworks.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Provided weekly demonstrations of our test automation and presented reports 
                for requirement coverage and testing progress.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Demonstrated the successful execution of our automated tests in an Azure 
                DevOps pipeline.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>T-Mobile Inc</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer in Test</Title>
            <Period>July 2018 - September 2019</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Designed and developed a robust test automation framework that uses Gradle, Java 11, 
                JUnit5, Selenide and Allure. This framework was instrumental in ensuring the reliability 
                and quality of our Layer3 TV STB (Set Top Box) product's user interface.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented unit tests using Jest to enhance code quality and identify potential issues 
                early in the development cycle. This proactive approach significantly contributed to a 
                reduction in production defects.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Championed test-driven development (TDD) practices within the organization by delivering 
                a highly informative "Lunch and Learn" session. Shared insights on the benefits of TDD and 
                practical strategies for its implementation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>The Judge Group</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer in Test (Contracted at Dish Network)</Title>
            <Period>January 2018 - July 2018</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed a test automation framework using Java, Maven, Selenium and Serenity BDD. 
                This framework was instrumental in ensuring the reliability and quality of Dish Network's 
                back office products.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Boosted productivity by implementing cucumber Gherkin files and skeleton step definitions
                that simply throw a pending exception. Our Serenity BDD framework was able to generate test reports 
                that showed the percentage of implemented steps. 
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>ITEC</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer (Contracted at Raytheon)</Title>
            <Period>June 2017 - January 2018</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Worked closely with systems engineers, integrators, testers and customers to design a 
                set of standards and guidelines for building CI/CD pipelines.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Learned the Phillip Kruechten's 4+1 architectural view model and applied it to my 
                software design and documentation.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer in Test (Contracted at Comcast)</Title>
            <Period>July 2016 - December 2016</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Designed custom UI, API and performance test automation frameworks, which resulted in 
                very rapid delivery of a critical software release.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Exceeded the expections of the client by delivering a high quality test 
                automation that developers and testers could use to verify the functionality of the
                video activation system.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Colorado Interactive</Company>
            <Title>Lead Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>Auguust 2014 - April 2016</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Redesigned the web application for registering businesses in Colorado by streamlining 
                the process for registering a business with Colorado Department of Labor and Employment, 
                Department of Revenue and Secretary of State. Previously business owners had to fill out 
                forms in two different web applications.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed new software enhancements and bug fixes for web applications used by the 
                Colorado state government.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Mentored junior engineers through code reviews, pair programming, and knowledge sharing 
                sessions, enhancing team productivity and skills development.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>KForce</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer in Test (Contracted at Charter Communications)</Title>
            <Period>February 2014 - August 2014</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created tests in Ruby and RSpec to test the functionality of microservices for ingesting 
                movie data from various sources.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Created tests for verifying the integrity of movie data in a Jackrabbit repository.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer (Contracted at Charles Schwab)</Title>
            <Period>February 2013 - December 2013</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed a robust software solution enabling Charles Schwab advisors to generate 
                comprehensive PDF reports for clients. These reports showcase current and proposed 
                investment portfolios, empowering clients to make informed decisions about their 
                financial investments.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Collaborated with cross-functional teams to implement an enterprise logging initiative. 
                This initiative aggregated logs from diverse applications and established a centralized 
                log viewer using Splunk. The centralized view allowed engineers and support teams to 
                efficiently troubleshoot issues and swiftly identify root causes by providing real-time 
                insights into events across multiple servers and applications.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>McKesson Corporation</Company>
            <Title>Senior Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>May 2010 to February 2013</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed new web service contracts (WSDL) and designed message payloads and 
                transformations for McKesson's Healthcare Management System.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Modernized healthcare management software to be compliant with the new ARRA 
                (American Rediscovery and Reinvestment Act) initiative.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>TEKsystems</Company>
            <Title>JUnit Developer (Contracted at Mckesson)</Title>
            <Period>January 2009 to May 2010</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Successfully implemented a data-driven integration testing framework that can 
                dynamically instantiate appropriate test objects based on the information in SOAP 
                headers. This was for testing message processing and routing in a messaging system (JMS).
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>        
        <Job>
            <Company>NetPolarity</Company>
            <Title>Java Engineer (Contracted at Charles Schwab)</Title>
            <Period>January 2008 - December 2008</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed new web services for aggregating gain/loss data for Charles Schwab's
                PortfolioCenter product.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed automated API tests using SoapUI.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Extended the capabilities of SoapUI by developing custom plugins in Java.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Electronic Data Systems</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>April 2005 - August 2007</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Successfully helped a team build a Message Oriented Middleware solution for a client. 
                Replaced an old CORBA architecture with a more modern JMS architecture.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented security in a single sign-on application. Configured Weblogic with 2-way SSL, 
                created Java keystores, and configured time synchronization and security policies in 
                Weblogic.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Company>Sun Microsystems</Company>
            <Title>Software Engineer</Title>
            <Period>January 2000 - April 2005</Period>
            <Accomplishments>
                <Accomplishment>
                Developed "Fact" classes and parsers for a rule engine used to perform 
                predictive analytics.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Learned a new programming language called KPL (Knowledge Predicate Language) 
                which I used in the rule engine for determining risk outcomes.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Responsible for requirements gathering, OOAD, development, testing, and deployment 
                of a 3-tier web application.
                </Accomplishment>
                <Accomplishment>
                Implemented software design patterns in a web application that empowered the 
                customer to generate a wide variety of report types.
                </Accomplishment>
            </Accomplishments>
        </Job>      
    </Section>

    <Section>
        <Education>
            <School>
                <Name>Sun Certified Java Programmer</Name>
                <Period>2006</Period>
                <Major></Major>
            </School>
            <School>
                <Name>Regis University</Name>
                <Period>2000 - 2001</Period>
                <Major>Completed 27 semester hours in Computer Science as funding permitted.</Major>
            </School>
        </Education>    
    </Section>
    
</Resume>
